[Music]
[Applause]
greetings and salutations this is a Bab
Dell hottie with the bitter truth where
we may not have all the answers but
we're gonna ask an awful lot of
questions you can also become a bitter
pill or fool spoonful of sugar if I
could talk today and get some fabulous
swag at patreon.com porch Lots the
bitter truth and make your life better
today I'm very excited we have a friend
of the show returning with us to talk
about some stuff and he is the host of
the loud and clear podcast which runs
Monday through Friday and he's also been
a former CIA officer he's Pakistani
station chief specifically we're gonna
get into that a little bit as well I'm
sure and he's also one of the first
whistleblowers that President Obama put
in jail and if you know that fabulous
track record you know he was a busy busy
boy compared to his predecessors the
great John Kerry aku is with us how are
you John hey doing well thanks thanks
for having me hey thanks for thanks for
coming on again man hey so um so you
know busy busy time but I know
specifically we wanted to kind of jump
into what's been going on lately with
with Julian Assange what's I know he was
he just won a Press Freedom Award right
yes he did he won a Press Freedom Award
that was very well deserved in my
opinion you know there's this debate
about whether or not Julian is a
journalist and I think that's the wrong
question the question is is he a
publisher and he's clearly a publisher
and if you're going to prosecute a
publisher it's a slippery slope to put
to to prosecuting and punishing anybody
else involved in in reporting the news
but it but still even as a journalist
though he's still afforded a press
freedom regardless if he's a publisher
journalist right yeah yeah that's right
but you know people get up get tied up
on these on these labels and they say
well he's not a real journalist what
newspaper does he work for what website
does he work for that's not the issue at
all the issue is is that he's working to
bring us truth right it's simple is that
mm-hmm well this is think to that it's
actually pretense because when I
remember when he was we need exposed
bushier or war crimes when Bush was
president not too long after that he got
his own TED talk and I'd seen that TED
talk a few times and
you know the so-called liberal audience
is breathlessly you know applauding and
oh my god he's a hero
I know then he turned his attention to
the Obama administration specifically
you know later with Hillary Clinton and
those very same people are like oh he's
a traitor he's not even journalist and
I'm like well right you I was a comedian
for a long time I played in a band I
never got a license for those things I
just got on stage and I was a comedian
right you know or at least I was
attempting to be and and I was a
musician for a long time didn't get a
license you know it's like this is they
act you go to journalism school the hell
does that mean you don't actually get a
license it's like you stick your head
out the window and whatever truth is
happening that day you pretty much write
that as best you can I mean it these
labels really just work me yes
oh I totally agree so I'm always hung up
on labels you know it seems especially
in Julian's case that it's it's become
more more bipolar I guess with with very
few people in the middle on this issue
mm-hmm well because I mean it's all
labels - it's all identity politics you
know like like like you know not to get
into these weeds but you see it all the
time if Tim Allen says something the
Conservatives are like oh my god he's in
America and the Brad Pitt says exactly
you know then they lose his [__] because
Brad Pitt's and something about the the
hearings and I don't agree with either
one of them but it's like it really just
depends on the flavor you know it's like
well why should Brad pitch you no bride
should Brad Pitt shut up on his opinion
but you breathlessly accept what Tim
Allen has to say right and then that Lee
right let me ask him before he got
dragged out of the embassy and you may
have mentioned this before and I
apologize had you ever spoken with him
before because I know you know I had
Snowden Baudette did you ever spoken
with him before the only time I ever
spoke with Julian was about six weeks
before he was pulled out of the embassy
we've exchanged a few letters since he's
been locked up in Belmarsh prison but
when he was in the embassy we only spoke
the one time Wow and then what what did
you gather his state to be when you
spoke to him last frightened
yeah when when when we when we exchanged
letters for the first
time let me think it was about I'm gonna
say ten months ago it was very clear
that he was he was a man in command he
he made a long list of things that he
wanted me to do
could I call this attorney could I ask
these questions could I call this
activist could I introduce him to such
in such a journalist that kind of thing
but it was a page and a half of that and
it was very actual in and then by the
third or fourth letter that we exchanged
he was frightened and worried he knew
that you know he knew Miranda was part
of pillars he knew marina was gonna pull
his [__] right he's that kind of the
idea yeah yeah it was like it was like
the fact that the fix is in was finally
he's thinking in mm-hm and you know I
think that the fix is not in I think
that there's a possibility certainly
that cooler heads can prevail and and
once word gets out as to the illegal
actions that the CIA and NSA and others
took against him in order to spy on him
for example when he was in the embassy
out of that that may be helpful okay
well let me so let me ask you something
I got kind of a laundry list of a [__]
ton of really good international laws
that I think are broken but let me let
me ask honestly so before before all
this before the pulling out of the
embassy but you know before Lenin Moreno
even won the election did he think he'd
have a shot at actually being free again
or was he kind of relegated to being in
the embassy uh I think deep down he
believed that there was a chance that he
would go free eventually you know he
thought he could outreach Barack Obama
and Donald Trump said a lot of nice
things about WikiLeaks and then it
became apparent that Donald Trump wasn't
gonna help him in any way and he thought
well he's gonna have to outweigh Donald
Trump and then at the same time
he was thinking you know I didn't do
these sexual assaults the the cops put
these women up to to filing the
complaints in the first place
once that sort of worked its way to to
the wayside that maybe there was a
chance through the British courts that
he could get out maybe he could get to
Iceland maybe he could get to Russia or
something like that and it just didn't
happen
well those anymore you know I mean I
think we were all shocked at Lennie
marinas response to this whole problem
well yeah because he wasn't he wasn't
Lenna marina wasn't some guy they just
fell out of the sky he was in the the
previous administration he was the VPD
and that are whatever well yeah well we
were named Lenin to be in the pocket of
the CIA right and that's exactly what he
was yeah and and that's and that's the
thing where when when when Korea left I
was just like all right well this guy's
gonna take over and you see that's mine
and that's my that's one of the
questions I wanted to start off with is
this trial that's happening I believe
it's the spring for Julian Assange
aren't they the trial is to see if the
British government is going to extradite
him to the United States right
correct correct and keep in mind that he
he had been held on charges of
bail-jumping right right and he was
sentenced to more than the maximum when
he was sentenced to 10 months which is
longer than the maximum sentence for
bail-jumping and then when he finished
that sentence they just said oh we're
not letting you out because we think
you're gonna run away so you just have
to remain here indefinitely in this
maximum-security penitentiary by the way
right he's not in he's not in the
majority can yeah and then I'm talking
about they put him in solitary
confinement will see me a note with
solitary confinement is it's a form of
torture we'll put in the bail-jumping
for a case that's been dropped three
times exactly it's not it's not new
charges it's it's bail-jumping for
something that the Swedish government
had dropped three times already
that's right that's right and I'll tell
you what worries me the most
well let me preface it by saying that
there is precedent there are precedents
plural for British courts refusing to
extradite subjects to the United States
because of the way the US uses solitary
confinement it is an internationally
recognized form of torture and so
British courts in the past have refused
to extradite people to the United States
it is conceivable that a British judge
could refuse to extradite Julian but
what would happen then since there are
no charges pending against him in the UK
right he would have to be released from
Belmarsh and then he would be expelled
because he is an Australian national and
the Australian government went to pains
about a year ago to renew his passport
he would be expelled to Australia and
then the US would ask Australia to
extradite him so you know there's no
easy fix to this not at all well and
then I'm just gonna ask him I got a
couple of other guys I wanted to talk
about really quick um most recently
Glenn Greenwald just got his charges
dropped on that Cyprus talking crap they
draw to accuse him of but with with
Julian Assange what I mean and this is
this is me being ignorant I'm asking
just to ask was was was the Ecuadorian
government revoking his citizenship
without cause is that illegal because
that's just seem pokey when they did it
you know it's funny well I don't know
specifically what Ecuadorian lawyers but
I just asked the same question of
another country that happens to be an EU
country and I just got a response a
formal response from the embassy today
and they said that it is not legally
possible to revoke citizenship that the
citizenship has to be renounced it can't
be revoked although I adore is not a
European Union country of course but I
would have to assume that there was
similarity from country to country sure
sure and then going into the embassy I
know I know
you know Mareno gave the Brit Police the
permission to go into the embassy yeah
is that is that the only way is that
illegal anyway I mean
it where is it I'm sorry technically
that would be that would be legal a
foreign power including a local power
like the police can only go into an
embassy with the express permission of
that country's leadership it's the only
way that it can be done
okay okay well then and then late and
then and last year when he was first put
in a Belmarsh and then they kept
dragging him nine dragging him that like
you know well they did they would drag
him out for like and let him talk for
ten seconds give his name and date of
birth or something but they're basically
trying them without even letting well I
don't know if they're doing it now but
last year they'd even let him look at
his prepared defense they didn't let him
talk to his attorneys they gave his
attorneys evidence that they'd asked for
it like 10 minutes before the hearings I
mean it was like total kangaroo court it
is isn't it is there is there a recourse
they can go to I mean this isn't the
this isn't the British Supreme Court or
their version of it is it it's like a
it's like a circuit court judge that's
doing this and isn't she's married to
somebody this is a magistrate yes you're
right so there are several levels above
this current judge that they can go and
now I've spoken with most of his
attorneys over the past year he has the
best attorneys that money can buy both
in the UK and in the United States so we
can all be assured that he's got some of
the best legal minds supporting him with
that said they have one hand tied behind
their backs because they're not
receiving discovery in a timely fashion
that's one of the reasons why these
hearings keep being postponed
now there's a hearing later this month
I'm gonna go to London in a couple weeks
to attend it's going to be short it's
going to be well short relatively it's
going to take about four days and then
there is a hearing in May that's
scheduled for two weeks and that's
supposed to be the whole hearing with
testimony exhibits and everything with
the result being either extradition or
no extradition mm-hmm okay um I'll shoot
I mean
seize it but then there's this thing
that frustrates me is the magistrate
who's married her husband you know has
has not benefited but her husband has
been a quote on the recipient end
receiving end of some of Julian
Assange's exposures should she should
shouldn't she be recusing herself wife I
would say yes right I would say
absolutely yet I don't know what Brit la
mean you know as far as that goes but
here in America if that was to go down
if you were being guide in your case for
example yeah if the judge if the judge
turned out to have been married to
someone who worked on the Obama campaign
right they would have to recuse
themselves absolutely you know
absolutely and that's that's exactly
what I would be calling for it's a
recusal and is britain have that kind of
a law do you know i don't know i don't
know you know what i don't know i don't
know okay but certainly i mean you know
this is a country that that's been
purportedly governed by the rule of law
for what eight hundred years now
magneton almost stuff like that listen
from the magna carta right and so he hid
the rest the world ought to be looking
to them for these kinds of issues rather
than a thing you know what's up with
this conflict of interest this isn't
cool well what is what is the legal what
is the legal us right to extradite i
mean it's not like he killed somebody on
US soil and then fled to britain the
$64,000 question does the u.s. have a
legal right to ask for his extradition
he's not an American citizen and here's
another thing a precedent was said in my
case a dangerous one but it was a great
expansion in the definition of espionage
so you know the definition of espionage
in the u.s. code goes on for pages my
judge made it is this and I quote her
exactly espionage is the provision of
any National Defense Information to any
person not entitled to receive it okay
so she didn't say anything about about
she didn't say anything about the First
Amendment it's just the provision of
National Defense information to any
person not entitled to receive it which
means under that definition that any
journalist let's say from The Washington
Post the New York Times The Wall Street
Journal can be charged with espionage
for publishing information that someone
I gave him or her that's still
classified and they used it in a news
story anybody so until my case it was
you know you had to have a criminal
intent to expose this information the
information had to be currently and
properly classified etc etc well Julian
was not was not subject to US law
demanding that he protect US defence
information classified information he
was under no obligation to protect
classified information so so why why
prosecute him in the first place even
the prosecution itself doesn't make any
sense to me well no and then and then to
speak to your point
he didn't give that information to an
enemy unquote he simply published it
yes but they argue that he gave it to an
enemy by publishing it and they argue
that that he exposed it to the likes of
the Russians and the Chinese and the
North Koreans etc okay well and part of
their and they still couldn't prove any
harm well that's another thing they
couldn't prove any harm in my case in
Tom Drake's case even in Chelsea
Manning's case Chelsea Manning turned
over hundreds of thousands of pages of
classified documents and they were never
able to prove that there was any harm to
the national security you know it'd be
so much easier if we quit [__] around
with people I think right it's like it
would be nice if we spent you know fifty
billion a year to give people water and
then no one would want to kill us
because they'd be like oh hey there the
water guys are cool and you know what
just as an aside that's how people view
the Chinese in the third world if you go
to yen
or Somalia Djibouti I've been all these
countries in the Eastern Horn of Africa
and they love to Chinese why because the
Chinese come and build roads and they
don't try to politicize them they don't
jump up it's down about about taxes or
human rights or military bases or any of
that stuff
no they just build roads in fact the
Chinese the Chinese only have two bases
outside of China right - that's right
and they just up there spend their
military budget spend to 225 billion
dollars yeah our military budget spend
is more than the next eight largest
countries combined oh yeah and and and
forget what the Congress just passed it
yeah I read Forbes of pub as publishes a
few times where it's closer to 1.2
trillion
1.1 trillion dollars a year when you
throw in covert VA and the name right
right right and we keep going and going
and going and then you know but I wanted
to kind of while we still have time with
you because kind of on this along the
same lines you know max Blumenthal just
had his charges dropped about a month
ago and it's just yesterday Glen Glen I
can't gosh I can't speak today Glen
Greenwald
just had his cyber spying charges or
whatever dropped in Brazil which kind of
shocked me because bolsa now is not
exactly a friend of the journalists but
um yeah and can you speak to those two
situations
sure sure I I'm happy to they're both
friends of mine max Blumenthal Wow poor
max max was accused of assaulting a
woman yeah in front of the Venezuelan
embassy in fact video showed that that
it was max who was assaulted he never
raised his hand to anybody a woman or
otherwise he was clearly assaulted the
police did nothing about it
and then weeks later they they carried
out a SWAT like raid on his house at six
o'clock in the morning you know with the
black helmets and flak jackets and and
the ar-15s or whatever I think it's an
ar-15 that the DC police used they
raided his house because someone had
written on the arrest warrant that he
was to be considered
and dangerous it's a miracle that they
didn't just open fire when they broke
down the door and went into the man's
home sure those charges were dropped
because he simply hadn't done what they
said he did the same day Medea Benjamin
was arrested and she was arrested for
allegedly assaulting congresswoman
debbie Wasserman Schultz that was
outrageous when I would've liked Hart I
would have more dropped I would have
liked to have seen that yeah I'm with
you I'm with you
and then there was Glenn Greenwald you
know Glenn's Glenn's made a lot of
people angry over the years a lot of
very very important people including
giant bolts in our house right um you
know the reason why I'm less sanguine
about Glenn safety is that the Minister
of Justice did not want to drop this
case the Minister of Justice was ordered
to drop it by one of the judges on the
Brazilian Supreme Court oh and even even
when they dropped the charge they still
sort of threatened him in their in their
reasoning for dropping the charge and
and so if I were clan I would I would be
very careful in in Brazil Brazil is
trending fascist and and the journalists
are going to be the first ones to go
well I mean my mother's from Brazilian I
mean mean like my brothers are first
generation here my dad's Palestinian
mothers Brazilians so we're a hot mess
but they the the the Lula da Silva days
were short and fairly recent you know I
mean up until up until DaSilva Brazil
had had a lot of these kinds of problems
before you know pretty much from 64 on
and so yeah yeah you know and and so
when de Silva came is sort of like a
like a like a Bulevar Ian you know you
know reform but it wasn't long before
you know they they they they jailed him
and pull it all the you know all the
John Perkins type crap that you read
about and we saw it in real time and
with Glenn Greenwald the thing that
makes me a little nervous about I'm and
you know his husband's a congressperson
in Brazil yes so it's not like they can
just up and leave
and and then where's no the other
question too is where is he gonna go you
know I mean it'd have to be somewhere
like Portugal or somewhere where where
is it while it's an EU country they
don't bend over to the will of the Brits
in the in the United States I mean it I
mean what do you think of that I was
having a conversation about the school
last night with a friend of mine and I
said what about Iceland
I mean ISIL has always been so friendly
with with people in this in this you
know these circles let's say right and
and Iceland was willing to take at
Snowden so just couldn't get there right
and so she said no no that Iceland has
changed Iceland has been refusing
request for asylum by by activists there
they're not interested in taking Glenn
Greenwald or ed Snowden or anybody else
that might cause them a political
problem was a country about half a
million people - it's not like that you
know that right you know I mean it's not
like it's not like they've got this you
know incredible military and and that
kind of thing either it's like you know
if we you know we'll look what we've
look what we've been doing with
international law of the last 20 years
we kind of don't give a [__] and I yeah
I could see us actually invade Iceland
to go get somebody
yeah I mean oh yeah and the buy-in would
be pretty easy I mean you know the other
night I just gave one wydo a standing
ovation and you know he's the recognized
president of Venezuela like no [__]
even win election in his own little deal
and you only had 40 there's how many
countries in the world 200 and only 40
our puppets recognize this guy yeah yeah
and and and it's such a white person
thing too because I mean when the when
the Bolivia thing happened last fall I'm
here in Austin you know supposedly super
blue Austin and I'm at a party with a
couple buddies and that came up and my
one friend he's like well you know I'm
not saying it was right but he was there
for a long time is it for 15 years ago
Angela Merkel's been running things for
15 years how come we don't pull the coup
in Germany Yeah right
well cuz she's white it's true you know
we don't like I agree we don't like the
brought black you don't want to go ahead
and like for anything to you that I
noticed when John Bolton was still
Vanessa
Security Advisor a reporter asked him
about the Venezuelan Constitution
because because Bolton had said that
quite del according to the Venezuelan
Constitution for ideal had every right
to be president and the reporter says
that the Venezuelan Constitution says
that you have 30 days in which to take
the oath of office and to begin
governing from the date of your election
he wasn't elected but it's been more
than 30 days since the coup so he's no
longer constitutionally eligible to be
President and Bolton just stood there
and stared at the guy like nobody had
ever bothered to read the Venezuelan
Constitution to see if even the
illegality of their coup could somehow
be massaged to make it look like it was
okay for one white doe to be President
this is American exceptionalism I swear
to God Bolton didn't know that that was
a gotcha question you're going to lead a
coup in a country and you don't even
know what the [__] law is that's what
these people exactly that's what these
people directly write you know and it's
a 70 like I said my dad's Palestinian
right now I don't have an emotional dog
in this fight at this point my life but
on a justice level I do
I mean this it's it's the same goddamn
thing as Bolivia or Nicaragua or
anywhere else and when people with a
straight face timing rules Lionism is
great I'm like really really that blows
my mind that you would say those words
in that way I mean if I said Nazis are
awesome what kind of response would I
get
I mean shooting six-year-olds in the
back from 100 feet 100 yards away with a
sniper rifle
yeah you don't I mean and when they go
on about well they they launched rockets
what volleyballs full of gunpowder I
mean you know what kind of rockets they
got in Gaza yeah right you know in
helmet and so far the Israelis have
killed 2.1 million Palestinians in the
last seven to seventy years okay right
not all of them PLO not all of them were
Hamas or Hezbollah and I'm sorry if it
wasn't for goddamn Hezbollah Lebanon
would have been annexed by now right so
just that kind of thing just drives you
and so-called liberals do it too like
we're talking about earlier with Tim
Allen versus Brad Pitt you know it's
right they'll built they do that too I
mean even Bernie Sanders can't even
bring himself say that that it was a
[__] coup you know he's like you
don't I mean he he could
even he couldn't even say well they need
they need an election reform no they
don't need a lecture reform dude he won
no he was one of the yes members of
Congress that stood up and gave a
standing ovation to one Guido the state
of the union yeah yeah all of them did I
didn't see anybody sit down yeah they
did you know and you know and you give
me this they need election reform and
then I got people with a straight face
that this is the one thing that pisses
me off when I hear people [__] about
Trump supporters and they'll say well
you know most of them aren't educated
and they don't have a degree I got a
degree for all the jack-shit it means
and let me tell you something I know a
lot of people with degrees who are
[__] stupid yep to sit there and MIT
use that as a measure of any
intelligence blows my mind especially
when you buy the news hook line and sink
like these guys do if Rachel Maddow says
it then it must be true right exactly
mm um let me let me let me let you do
your thing really quick you know I
appreciate the time we're getting close
to the end here but so um where can we
find your podcast and did I say I said
Monday through Friday I've heard it
before but um I listen on YouTube so I
don't I don't always catch it live like
um so yeah so it's called loud and clear
with Brian Becker we do it Monday
through Friday it's it's on terrestrial
radio here in the Washington area and
also in Kansas City but it's available
as a podcast at iTunes I Heart Radio
Spreaker Spotify all the various
platforms allow seems clear with Brian
Becca
okie dokie and I'll put that and I'll
also put that in the link in the body of
the show too
um but hey John seriously appreciate
your time preciate you coming on and
folks again our guest has been John
Kerry aku and you can again visit us on
patreon com forward slash the bitter
truth and if this stuff makes
uncomfortable its supposed to sleep
tight
[Applause]
[Music]
you